Finding Aid for the Albert Boime Papers LSC.1834
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Research materials, 1941-2008
  - Dada and Surrealism, 1993-2006
    - Dada/Surrealism seminar, 1998 (Box 71, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, photocopies, notes, and bibliographies. Some materials in French.
    - Dada/Surrealism seminar, 1999 (Box 71, Folder 7)
      Notes, photocopies, class roster, week 1 course outline with Boime's notes, and Surrealism exhibition catalog.
    - Dada, 1999 (Box 71, Folder 8)
      Correspondence and bibliography.
    - Dada, 2000 (Box 71, Folder 9)
      Photocopy, notes, clipping, and annotated bibliography by Acacia Warwick.
    - Dada, ca. 1998-1999 (Box 72, Folder 1)
      Paper on Dada by Rachael Steele, photocopy of article about Marcel Duchamp, and exhibition brochure from "Joseph Cornell/Marcel Duchamp…in resonance" at the Philadelphia Museum of Art.
    - Dada redux, 2000-2002 (Box 72, Folder 2)
      E-mail correspondence, photocopies of letters from 1914-1915, draft of "Dada's Dark Secret", and notes.
    - Dada - Surrealism, 2002, 2006 (Box 72, Folder 3)
      Notes, photocopies, correspondence, and Hammer Museum Exhibition catalog.
    - Surrealism, 1980, 1989, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 4)
      Notes, photocopies, clippings, pamphlet and related materials from exhibition "The Shadow of Gradiva" at the Getty Center (artists of interest include Salvador Dali and Max Ernst), and e-mail correspondence.
    - Surrealism and Mexico, 2001 (Box 72, Folder 5)
      Dissertation prospectus for Acacia Warwick: "Prefabricated Desire: Surrealism, Mannequins, and the Fashioning of Modernity."
    - Waintrub - Surrealism, 1993 (Box 72, Folder 6)
      PhD examination, bibliographies, and papers on surrealism for Alexander Waintrub.
    - Dali - Angelus, undated (Box 72, Folder 7)
      Copy of "Salvador Dali: Le Mythe Tragique de l'Angelus de Millet" by Jean-Jacques Pauvert. All materials in French.
    - Marcel Duchamp, undated (Box 72, Folder 8)
      Notes, photocopies, and clippings.
    - Marcel Duchamp, undated (Box 72, Folder 9)
      Notes and correspondence. Some materials in French.
    - Leonardo, Freud, and Duchamp, undated (Box 72, Folder 10)
      Notes on Leonardo, Freud, and Duchamp. Folder also includes Leonardo Da Vinci catalog from National Gallery of Art.
    - Rene Magritte, undated (Box 72, Folder 11)
      Photocopy of article by Michel Foucault about Rene Magritte. Some materials in French. Folder originally titled Sir Maggie.
    - Magritte, 1997 (Box 72, Folder 12)
      Catalog of Magritte works by UCLA Hammer Museum.
  - Comics, 1973-2006, bulk 1981-1995
    Materials include comic books collected by Boime and general research materials on comic strips, graphic novels, and animation, possibly for a class on comics. The subseries is filed by type of material beginning with comic books and ending with research files.
    - Comic books 1, 1985, 1992 (Box 72, Folder 13)
      DC and Marvel comic books including Superman, Swamp Thing, Nomad, Kitty Pryde and Wolverine, Phoenix, and Spiderman.
    - Comic books 2, 1989-1990, 1993, 1995 (Box 73, Folder 1)
      Assortment of comic books by Eightball, America's Best Comics, and Fantagraphics Books.
    - Comic books 3, 1996 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      Comic book magazines Wizard, Amalgam, and Beautiful Decay.
    - Comic books 4, 1984-1986, 1993 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      DC Comic books featuring Swamp Thing and The Sandman.
    - Comic books 5, 1986, 1992-1993 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Marvel comic books featuring The Fantastic Four and The Hood comic book by South Central Comics.
    - Comic books 6, 1991-1993 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      DC comic books featuring Sandman character.
    - Comic books 7, 1989-1991, 1993, 1995 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      Eightball comic books by Fantagraphic Books.
    - Comics, undated (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Comics, undated (Box 73, Folder 8)
      Comics by Boime and photos.
    - Comics, undated (Box 73, Folder 9)
      Comics by Boime.
    - Comic strip, 1982, 1987 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      Photocopies, correspondence, notes, clippings, and comic strip books.
    - Comic strip II, ca. 1981 (Box 74, Folder 2)
      Clippings and proposal by Jeremy Kay for a comic book course.
    - Comics miscellaneous, 1981, 1988, 1993, 2003 (Box 74, Folder 3)
      Photocopies, comic magazines, articles, clippings, correspondence, 4x5 transparencies, and copies of images.
    - Comic book seminar, 1992, 2000, 2006 (Box 74, Folder 4)
      Photocopies, clippings, and correspondence.
    - Comic book seminar, 1973-1976, 1993-2003 (Box 74, Folder 5)
      Clippings, notes, and articles.
    - Art History 127 - comics, 1997 (Box 74, Folder 6)
      Clippings, notes, and student writings.
    - Melodrama, 1991-1998 (Box 75, Folder 1)
      Copies of "From Hell" (melodrama in 16 parts) including Volumes 1-3, 6-7, and 11.
    - Graphic novel seminar, 2005-2006 (Box 75, Folder 2)
      Hammer Museum Winter 2005-2006 Calendar of events/exhibitions, printouts on history of DC Comics, and comics.
    - Animation, 1979-1982 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Feiffer, undated (Box 75, Folder 4)
      Notes and slide.
    - Cartoons, undated (Box 75, Folder 5)
      Photo prints of cartoons, application for leave of absence, and notes.
  - Corporate Art, 1980-2006
    Boime's research on corporations and corporate art collections, including brochures and catalogs about specific collections. The subseries is filed by topic.
    - Corporate art, 1982, 1984 (Box 141, Folder 6)
      Brochures and correspondence regarding corporate art collecting (especially in Houston, Texas), photocopies, and notes.
    - Corporate art, 1982 (Box 75, Folder 6)
      Prospectus for Art History 125 class on corporate art collecting and brochures regarding Cedars Sinai Medical Center.
    - Corporate art (1 of 2), 1990, 1994 (Box 75, Folder 7)
      Photocopies, booklets regarding Atlantic Richfield Foundation and its art patronage, reports and pamphlets regarding corporate art, and Art History 253 syllabi.
    - Corporate art (2 of 2), 1990, 1994 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Corporate art, ca. 1982 (Box 75, Folder 9)
      Fine Art Services Incorporated program information and photocopies of articles regarding corporate art collecting.
    - Corporate art, ca. 1994 (Box 75, Folder 10)
      Photocopies, class roster, notes, clippings, and flyer and bibliography for Boime's seminar on censorship.
    - Art 253 Recasting, bulk 1993-1994, 2001 (Box 76, Folder 1)
      Photocopies, articles, clippings, notes, and correspondence.
    - Corporate, ca. 1991 (Box 76, Folder 2)
      Transparency, photocopy of corporate art holdings by corporation, and clippings.
    - Corporate, 1984-1990 (Box 76, Folder 3)
      Brochures and booklets for items in the CIGNA collection. Folder also includes correspondence and information about CIGNA Collection.
    - Corporate, 1984 (Box 76, Folder 4)
      Materials from Conference on Corporate Art Collecting, articles, Sotheby's newsletter, booklets, and brochures.
    - Economics - savings and loans, ca. 1990, 1997, 2003 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Corporation, 1980-1981, 1991-1992, 1998, 2004-2005 (Box 76, Folder 6)
      Student Papers, correspondence, photocopies and information on Philip Morris and art, clippings, and newsletters.
    - Philip Morris, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 7)
      Clippings, catalog of art at Philip Morris, and correspondence.
    - Cigarettes, 1998, 2002 (Box 76, Folder 8)
      Clippings and cigarette ads.
    - Enron, Wal-Mart, 2002, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 9)
      Clipping and Issue No. 68 of Co-op America Quarterly.
    - Disney, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 10)
      Internet Articles, essays, and blog posts regarding Disney.
    - Disney parks, ca. 1990 (Box 76, Folder 11)
      Clippings and articles regarding Disney hotels.
    - Consumerism, 1993 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Houston Art Dealer's Association, undated (Box 77, Folder 2)
      Brochures and catalogs for various Houston-based art galleries.
  - Jewish Art and Anti-Semitism, 1988-2003
    Materials related to Boime's research on Jewish art, artists, and anti-semitism. Subseries includes informational materials, drafts, and correspondence for Ken Aptekar's "Too Jewish" exhibition. The subseries is arranged by topic.
    - "Too Jewish" exhibition, 1996 (Box 77, Folder 3)
      Notes, papers by Eunice Lipton including "The Pastry Shop and the Angel of Death: What's Jewish in Art History", instructional material, flyers, brochures, and press release for "Too Jewish" exhibition at the Hammer Museum.
    - Aptekar - "Too Jewish", 1997 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      Correspondence regarding an essay by Boime for the catalog of an exhibition by Ken Aptekar at the Corcoran Museum of Art (likely the "Too Jewish?" exhibition). Folder also includes multiple drafts of "Aptekar's Family Album" with edits (essay for catalog), notes, and photos/press releases for exhibition.
    - "Too Jewish" exhibition correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Jewish art, 1998 (Box 77, Folder 6)
      Draft of Michael Blacher's paper "Russian Conceptions of Jewish Origins, 1893-1932: An Encyclopedic Examination" and brochures.
    - Jewish art, 1976, 1988, 1994 (Box 77, Folder 7)
      Correspondence and copy of catalog essay on Sidney Chafetz by Henry Klein. Other materials include notes, class syllabi, and articles.
    - Jewish art, ca. 1999-2002 (Box 77, Folder 8)
      Clippings, pamphlets, research project outline by Carol Zemel, correspondence, and photocopied articles.
    - Jewish art in Russia, undated (Box 77, Folder 9)
      Photocopies of works by M. Antokolsky.
    - Chasidic art, 2000 (Box 77, Folder 10)
      Notes, photocopies, and correspondence.
    - Jews and avant-garde, ca. 1998 (Box 77, Folder 11)
      Photocopies, brochures and pamphlets, and papers (likely by students).
    - American Jewish identity, undated (Box 78, Folder 1)
      Draft of "Chapter III: From Tragedy to Triumph: Demystifying American Jewish Identity."
    - Jews - USA cinema, bulk 1989-1990, 1997 (Box 78, Folder 2)
      Jewish Museum brochure/newsletter, images, Jews in American Cinema conference schedule, correspondence, and student exam.
    - Women - Jews, undated (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Kabbalah, 2002 (Box 78, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, notes, and photocopies.
    - Temple, 2000-2002 (Box 78, Folder 5)
      Correspondence, photocopies, notes, syllabus for Art History 127: The Temple Mount, Joshua Schwartz Curriculum Vitae, course outline, and general timeline of Temple Mount.
    - Yiddish, ca. 1993 (Box 78, Folder 6)
      Photocopies, notes, and writings "Jews in the Ghetto." Some materials in Hebrew.
    - Maus, 1998 (Box 78, Folder 7)
      Draft of chapter "Der Sturmer and the Stormtroopers", correspondence, library research printouts, notes, draft of "A Psychoanalytic View of Racial Myths in a Nazi Propaganda Film: Der ewige Jude (The Eternal Jew)" by John J. Hartman, and photocopies. Topics of materials are generally related to Art Spiegelman's MAUS books.
    - Shica Greenberg, undated (Box 78, Folder 8)
      Draft of "Shica Greenberg and Jewish Art" and photographic prints.
    - Anti-Semitism, 1998-2000 (Box 78, Folder 9)
      Photocopies, draft of "Embetements semitiques: Author-Publisher Relations in fin-de-siècle France: The Case of Gyp and Calmann-Levy," copy of Journal of Jewish Art, History 191F syllabus, clippings, and e-mail correspondence.
    - Anti-Semitism, 2002-2003 (Box 79, Folder 1)
      Photocopies, clippings, and e-mail correspondence.
    - Anti-Semitism chapter, undated (Box 79, Folder 2)
      Draft of "Chapter VI: British Modernism, Anti-Materialism, and Anti-Semitism."
    - Art of the Third Reich, 1997 (Box 79, Folder 3)
      UCLA Library Research and dissertation proposal by Sandra Esslinger with edits.
  - German Art, 1978-1992
    Boime's research on German art, including topics like Napoleon, Little Boney, and Alfred Rethel. Arranged by topic.
    - German art, 1978 (Box 79, Folder 4)
      Notes, annotated photocopies (topics include Caspar David Friedrich and German naturalism), and draft of paper "Caspar David Friedrich: The Monk on the Seashore." Some materials in French and German.
    - German art, bulk 1979, 1988 (Box 79, Folder 5)
      Photocopies, notes, and correspondence. Most materials in German.
    - Germans, 1985 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      Notes and pages from untitled draft. Materials in German.
    - Germans, 1985 (Box 79, Folder 7)
      Pages from untitled draft, notes, and photocopies.
    - 19th century Germany, 1985-1986 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Napoleon, 1989 (Box 79, Folder 9)
      Notes and correspondence. Materials in German.
    - Adolphe von Menzel, undated (Box 80, Folder 1)
      Notes and untitled draft.
    - Germany, Napoleon, and Romans, 1985-1987 (Box 80, Folder 2)
      Draft of untitled paper with edits, draft of "The Astory of Perth-Amboy," notes, draft of "Enlightenment to Romantic," and photocopies.
    - Little Boney - 2nd edition, 1992 (Box 80, Folder 3)
      Draft of Prospectus "James Gilray's Little Boney 1803-1805: A Study in the Manipulation of Collective Attitudes," photocopies of Little Boney caricatures, draft of "Antoine-Jean Gros and the Napoleonic Image" by Ann Friedman, draft of paper by Peter Klein, and list of Napoleonic laws in Rome. Materials in German.
    - Dusseldorf, 1978-1979, 1988 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, notes, copy of New York Historical Society Quarterly (Volume 58, No. 4), and annotated photocopies. Some materials in German.
    - Hasenclave Dusseldorf, 1978-1979, 1987-1988 (Box 80, Folder 5)
      Notes, photocopies, and correspondence. Some materials in German
    - Durkheim, undated (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - German prints, 1988 (Box 80, Folder 7)
      Copies of images requested by Boime from the German Information Center.
    - Miscellaneous research, 1978-1979 (Box 80, Folder 8)
      Notes, photocopies, and correspondence. Topics of contents include Rethel, Dusseldorf, Hasenclaver, and German Romantic Painting.
    - Slides and images, 1988 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Alfred Rethel, 1990 (Box 81, Folder 1)
      Correspondence and draft of "Alfred Rethel's Counterrevolutionary Death Dance."
    - Alfred Rethel, undated (Box 81, Folder 2)
      Notes and annotated photocopies. Some materials in German.
    - Alfred Rethel's Counterrevolutionary Death Dance, undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
      Draft of "Alfred Rethel's Counterrevolutionary Death Dance" by Boime with some edits.
  - The French Commune, 1990-2000
    Materials related to Boime's research on the French Commune, likely for his book "Art and the French Commune." Arranged topically.
    - Commune, 1973, 2000 (Box 142, Folder 1)
      Slides, 4x5 transparencies, draft of "The Commune and the Impressionists" with edits, photocopies of card catalog index cards, and newspaper clipping.
    - Art and the French Commune, undated (Box 81, Folder 4)
      Photocopies of pages from "Art and the French Commune" with edits and notes.
    - French Commune, 1995-1996 (Box 81, Folder 5)
      Correspondence, photocopies, notes, and proof pages from "Art and the French Commune" with edits. Some materials in French.
    - Commune, 1993 (Box 81, Folder 6)
      Notes, photocopies, and correspondence. Some materials in Italian and French.
    - Commune, 1990s (Box 81, Folder 7)
      Copy of Paris Observer from 1971, photocopies, copies of images, 4x5 images, clippings, and notes.
    - Commune - Olin, undated (Box 81, Folder 8)
      Notes, draft of "AAA-OLW-Paris Commune" with edits, and photocopies.
    - Commune additions, 1994 (Box 82, Folder 1)
      Notes, draft of introduction for volume, photocopies, proof of French Commune volume, and 4x5 transparencies. Some materials in French.
    - SUNY - Commune, 1990, 1993 (Box 82, Folder 2)
      Photocopies, copies of images, notes, clippings, student paper, correspondence, images, and 4x5 transparencies. Some materials in French.
    - The Commune and 1848, undated (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Illustrations, 1993-1994 (Box 82, Folder 4)
      Copies of photographs from the French Commune, illustration list, correspondence, 4x5 transparency, and notes.
    - French Commune proof, 1996 (Box 82, Folder 5)
      Correspondence and proof of "Art and the French Commune" from Princeton University Press.
    - Reader's reports, 1994 (Box 82, Folder 6)
      Notes, correspondence, and reader's reports for "Art and the French Commune."
    - Princeton University correspondence, bulk 1994-1996, 1991 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Landscape, 1988-1997
    Materials related to Boime's research on landscape painting, likely for one of his publications. The subseries also includes research on Walt Whitman and his relationship to landscape. Materials are filed by topic.
    - The new American landscape, ca. 1988-1990 (Box 142, Folder 2)
      Notes, annotated photocopies, papers, and reprint request letters.
    - Landscape photos, ca. 1988 (Box 142, Folder 3)
      Photos, correspondence, notes, and annotated photocopies.
    - Landscape notes, undated (Box 142, Folder 4)
    - Walt Whitman notes, undated (Box 142, Folder 5)
      Notes on American Renaissance, Gustave Courbet, and Walt Whitman. Folder also includes a Whitman bibliography.
    - Landscape, undated (Box 82, Folder 8)
      Photocopies of slide labels by landscape artists, notes, and project description for proposed exhibition.
    - Landscape project, 1976, 1979 (Box 82, Folder 9)
      Photocopies of "Der Mond" article, student paper, notes (topics include the moon and lunar society), class syllabus, correspondence, and call slips. Some materials in German.
    - Landscape project part II, undated (Box 83, Folder 1)
      Notes and photocopies. Folder also includes draft of "The Moon and Sixpence: Lunar Madness in the 19th Century Painting." Some materials in German.
    - American landscape, ca. 2000 (Box 83, Folder 2)
      Notes, exhibition summary, and proposal from John Ott (Ph.D. candidate) for research.
    - American landscape, ca. 1988 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Landscape illustrations, ca. 1980 (Box 83, Folder 4)
      Photos, notes, photocopies, and correspondence.
    - Landscape additions, ca. 1990-1991 (Box 83, Folder 5)
      Notes, photocopies, prospectus of book by Alan Wallach, annotated photocopies (topics include Thomas Cole), correspondence, and photo reproduction documents.
    - Landscape permissions, 1990-1991 (Box 83, Folder 6)
      Correspondence regarding photo permissions and draft of book summary.
    - Landscape contract and correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 83, Folder 7)
      Correspondence and publishing contract for "Manifest Destiny and the Magisterial Gaze in 19th Century American Landscape Painting."
    - Constable - Turner (English painting), undated (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Walt Whitman, 1989 (Box 83, Folder 9)
      Notes and draft of "Leaves of Grass and Real Allegory: A Case Study of International Rebellion." Some materials in French.
    - Walt Whitman, 1988 (Box 83, Folder 10)
      Notes, photocopies, correspondence, and draft "Chapter Three: New England Transcendentalism and New York Rowdyism: Corot, Courbet, and the Search for the Poetic Style."
    - Draft, 1989 (Box 83, Folder 11)
      Correspondence and draft of article titled "Leaves of Grass and Real Allegory: A Case Study of International Rebellion."
    - West as America reviews, ca. 1991, 1997 (Box 83, Folder 12)
      Notes, photocopies of articles, proposal, brochure, and student research project proposal.
    - Lecture, undated (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Survey, undated (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Crazies, undated (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - Expeditions, undated (Box 83, Folder 16)
      Notes regarding various expeditions including the Washburn Expedition and Fremont Expedition.
  - July Monarchy, 1981-2008
    The subseries is filed by subject as general July Monarchy, 1848 topics, and 1830 topics.
    - July Monarchy, 1991 (Box 142, Folder 6)
      Photocopies, notes, and miscellaneous pages from paper on Delacroix and Ingres. Some materials in French.
    - July Monarchy, undated (Box 83, Folder 17)
      Drafts of articles and chapters, annotated photocopies, and notes. Folder also includes draft of "Chapter IV: The Counter-Revolution of the July monarchy: An Umbrella Organization (1830-1848)" and 2 other July Monarchy Papers.
    - July Monarchy, 1990 (Box 84, Folder 1)
      Notes, photocopies of book, and correspondence regarding Boime's attendance at symposium about July Monarchy. Some materials in French.
    - July Monarchy, ca. 1993 (Box 84, Folder 2)
      Dissertation proposal from Dennis Sexsmith and dissertation abstract from Barbara Ann Day.
    - July Monarchy Press, undated (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Germany 1848, undated (Box 84, Folder 4)
      Articles, notes (topics include Romanticism and Friedrich), draft of paper "Social identity and Political Authority in the response of Two Prussian Painters to the Revolution of 1848." Some materials in German. See box 42 for additional research on this topic.
    - 1848 - Germany, undated (Box 84, Folder 5)
      Draft of "Left, Right, and Center: The Response of Three Prussian Painters to the Revolution of 1848." See box 42 for additional research on this topic.
    - Contest 1848, 1968 (Box 84, Folder 6)
      Notes, correspondence, copies of images, photocopies, and draft of "The Second Republic's Contest for the Figure of the Republic" with edits. Some materials in French. See box 42 for additional research on this topic.
    - New 1848, ca. 1989 (Box 84, Folder 7)
      Draft of "Social Identity and Political Authority in the Response of Two Prussian painters to the Revolution of 1848" and correspondence. See box 42 for additional research on this topic.
    - Beidermeier, undated (Box 84, Folder 8)
      Notes, map of Copenhagen, and photocopies. Some materials in German.
    - Beidermeier 1848, 2000 (Box 84, Folder 9)
      Correspondence, article, and color photocopy of image from Jewish Museum. See box 42 for additional research on this topic.
    - Last chapter 1830-1848, ca. 1985 (Box 84, Folder 10)
      Drafts, notes, photocopies, correspondence, and bibliographies (topics include Juste Milieu, 1848, Realism, and Ingres). See box 42 for additional research on this topic.
    - Contests 1830, undated (Box 85, Folder 1)
      Pages from draft on Contests, notes, and annotated photocopies.
    - 1830 Contest, 1981-1983 (Box 85, Folder 2)
      Notes, photocopies, correspondence, and drafts of "The Quasi-Open competitions of the Quasi-Legitimate July Monarchy" with edits. Some materials in French.
    - 1830 miscellaneous, ca. 2008 (Box 85, Folder 3)
      Call slips, notes, photos, and correspondence regarding appraisal of Couture painting.
    - Notes, undated (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Opera comique, undated (Box 85, Folder 5)
      Contract and notes. Materials in French.
  - Graduate School Research, bulk 1960-1970, 1979-1988
    Materials corresponding to research conducted by Boime during his graduate studies and early academic career. The subseries is arranged by subject.
    - Archivo Academia Di Belle Arti, undated (Box 142, Folder 7)
      Annotated photocopies. Materials in Italian.
    - Conference paper, ca. 1979 (Box 142, Folder 8)
      Correspondence, proof sheet, notes, and draft of paper given at a Latin American Studies Assoc conference in Pittsburgh (1979) entitled "The Effects of the Social Sciences on Pre-Columbian Art History."
    - Notes, 1987-1988 (Box 143, Folder 1)
      Notes, correspondence, and drafts. Some materials in French.
    - Notes, undated (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Georg Sauter, 1968 (Box 85, Folder 6)
      Notes and draft on Georg Sauter and his "Bridal Morning" including correspondence with his wife Ralda Sauter.